{"test_questions": [[{"question": "Both strands of DNA serve as templates concurrently in", "opta": "replication", "optb": "excision repair", "optc": "mismatch repair", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Proofreading activity to maintain the fidelity of DNA synthesis", "opta": "occurs after the synthesis has been completed", "optb": "is a function of the 3'-5' exonuclease activity of the DNA polymerases", "optc": "requires the presence of an enzyme separate from the DNA polymerases", "optd": "occurs in prokaryotes but not eukaryotes", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following repairs nicked DNA by forming a phosphodiester bond between adjacent nucleotides?", "opta": "Helicase", "optb": "DNA gyrase", "optc": "Topoisomerases", "optd": "DNA ligase", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The enzyme that catalyzes the synthesis of DNA is called", "opta": "DNA polymerase", "optb": "DNA gyrase", "optc": "DNA ligase", "optd": "helicase", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following possesses both 5'-3' and 3'-5' exonuclease activity?", "opta": "Kornberg enzyme", "optb": "DNA polymerase III", "optc": "Taq DNA polymerase", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following statements on replication in E.coli is correct?", "opta": "It occurs in a unidirectional manner", "optb": "It occurs in bidirectional manner", "optc": "Always uses T7 DNA polymerase when infected by T7 phage", "optd": "Occurs only when \u03bb phase has infected E. coli", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The replication of chromosomes by eukaryotes occurs in a relatively short period of time because", "opta": "the eukaryotes have more amount of DNA for replication", "optb": "the eukaryotic replication machinery is 1000 times faster than the prokaryotes", "optc": "each chromosome contains multiple replicons", "optd": "eukaryotic DNA is always single stranded", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In E.coli, which enzyme synthesizes the RNA primer for Okazaki fragments?", "opta": "DnaA", "optb": "DnaC", "optc": "DnaG", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "During which of the following process a new copy of a DNA molecule is precisely synthesized?", "opta": "Trasformation", "optb": "Transcription", "optc": "Translation", "optd": "Replication", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "DNA gyrase is inhibited by", "opta": "tetracycline", "optb": "nalidixic acid", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "cephalosporin", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following enzymes unwind short stretches of DNA helix immediately ahead of a replication fork?", "opta": "DNA polymerases", "optb": "Helicases", "optc": "Single-stranded binding proteins", "optd": "Topoisomerases", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "During DNA replication in prokaryotes, synthesis begins on the circular chromosome", "opta": "always at the same place", "optb": "at any stretch of DNA that is high in AT pairs", "optc": "randomly on the chromosome", "optd": "at the promoter", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "DNA replication rates in prokaryotes are approximately of the order of", "opta": "10 bases per second", "optb": "1,00 bases per second", "optc": "1,000 bases per second", "optd": "10,000 bases per second", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following lacks 3'-5' exonuclease activity?", "opta": "Short fragment of DNA polymerase I", "optb": "Taq DNA polymerase", "optc": "T4 DNA ligase", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The synthesis of DNA by DNA polymerase occurs in the", "opta": "3' to 5' direction", "optb": "5' to 5' direction", "optc": "5' to 3' direction", "optd": "3' to 3' direction", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}